# CHRISTOPHER E. RILLING

MORRISON, CO • (303) 748-7838 • COULOMBCOEFFICIENT@YAHOO.COM LINKEDIN.COM/IN/CHRIS-RILLING-6B542523/

## **G**EOLOGIST

#### **OIL AND GAS INDUSTRY**

Accomplished Geologist with over 14 years of office, field and laboratory experience in the oil and gas industry. Consistently advanced to roles of increased responsibility because of demonstrated initiative and independent thinking. Flexible, adaptable professional who makes sound judgements in fast-changing situations. Trains domestic and international teams in data collection and analysis as well as jobsite safety. Builds strong relationships with leading oil and gas companies worldwide. Former Section Chief, Colorado National Guard. Certified in Advanced Japanese, Hazardous Materials and Radiation Safety.

## Areas of Expertise

Sorption Services • Team Leadership • Petroleum Geology • Drilling • Reservoir Management • Formation Evaluation Mud Logging • Gas Chromatography • Sedimentology • Training • Hazardous Materials • Troubleshooting Pressure Core Analysis • Sample Collection and Analysis • International Projects • International Shipping

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### CORE LABORATORIES - Denver, CO

## Group Leader II, Petroleum Services Division

Direct wellsite and laboratory operations for sorption services and routine rock properties.

- Originally hired as desorption specialist (via Aerotek), regularly promoted to roles of increased responsibility, including Analyst I and II and then to Group Leader II.
- Served as well-site desorption lead on 60+ jobs, including desorption, rock properties and RSWC/Full core pressure core projects in U.S. and internationally.
- Field operations include equipment maintenance, pressure core analysis, operation, inventory, sample collection and analysis, logistics and information distribution between lab and clients.
- Lab operations include measuring desorbed gas, residual gas, collecting plug samples for analysis, slabbing, various other petrophysical measurements, and troubleshooting equipment.
- Improved jobsite safety and efficiency by rewriting SOPs for field desorption analysis and providing field training for new desorption specialists, adjusting as needed as older, defective equipment was replaced by newer versions.
- Ensured data accuracy and operational consistency by implementing onshore training for pressure core analysis for U.S. and international field and lab personnel.
- Experienced in onshore domestic sorption and routine rock properties in PA, ND, WY, CO, TX, WV, NY, UT, NM, LA, AL, IL, MO, KS, MT, and OH.
- Personally requested by international client companies for special projects. Successfully demonstrated rationale for alternative geological testing methods to clients in China, Kuwait and Abu Dhabi.
- International onshore experience in Abu Dhabi, Kuwait, Paraguay, China, Colombia, Canada, Poland, France, Australia, and Zimbabwe.
- Served as Hazardous Materials Shipper and Radiation Safety Officer.
- Selected to oversee CT scanning operations and training.

#### PASON SYSTEMS USA CORP – Golden, CA

2004 - 2009

2010 - Present

#### Geologist

Served as Mud Logger, creating detailed record (well log) of boreholes by examining rock cuttings brought to surface, analyzing stratigraphic formations and gas supplies. Also diagnosed and repaired problems in computer and gas detection equipment, advising on-site drilling supervisors and company geologist.

- Designated as Total Remote Geologist, observing multiple drilling rigs and performed remote geosteering, providing detailed reports in daily morning meetings.
- Successfully monitored and controlled 30 rigs simultaneously.
- Also served at help desk, assisting field technicians in fixing equipment and dispatching them to rigs in need of maintain and parts.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

#### COLORADO ARMY NATIONAL GUARD

1996-2004/2009 – Dec 2012

Section Chief, MLRS (Multiple Launch Rocket System) /HIMARS (High Mobility Artillery Rocket System).

Oversaw equipment inventory and maintenance as well as troop welfare.

- Supervised 2 to 8 personnel.
- Worked closely with local law enforcement during Operation Noble Eagle (Nov. 2001-May 2002), providing security for Montrose and Gunnison, CO, airports post 9/11.
- Held dual MOS (Military Occupational Specialty) codes: 13B (cannon crew) and 13M (multiple launch rockets) simultaneously
- Designated as second in command, Howitzer operations.
- Successfully fulfilled role while also serving as Group Leader II, Core Laboratories (above).

## EDUCATION AND PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

BS, Geology, Adams State University

### Core Laboratories Training:

Dual Energy CT Scanning and Analysis, 2018 Pressure Core Handling and Procedures, 2014 Desorption Field Services and Analysis, 2010

## Colorado Army National Guard Training:

Basic Non-Commissioned Officer Course (BNCOC)

Primary Leadership Development Course (PLDC)

#### **Berlitz Language Institute:**

Certificate, Advanced Japanese

## PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIPS

American Association of Petroleum Geologists (AAPG)

Rocky Mountain Association of Geologists (RMAG)

Geological Society of America (GSA)